Henry Goodman collection of theater playbills, circa 1762 – circa early-1900s, 1951; bulk dates circa 1830s-1865
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Playbills., circa 1762, 1786, 1790s, early 1800s-1865, 1871, early 1880s, 1895, early 1900s, and undated.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Beauty and the Beast., 1841 May 6. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Additional listing: London Assurance. Individuals listed: Mr. J. Bland, Miss Grant, Mr. Harley, Mr. W. Harrison, Mr. Lee, Miss Rainforth, Madame Vestris, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Coriolanus., 1806 Nov 12. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Individuals listed: Mr. Claremont, Mr. Kemble, Mr. Pope, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - The Coronation of Queen Anne Bullen., 1831 Oct 24. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Color. Additional listings: King Henry VIII and A Genius Wanted. Individuals listed: Mrs. Gibbs, Mr. C. Kemble, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - The Fashionable Lover., 1786 May 9. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Additional listings: Annette and Lubin; The Country Madcap. Individuals listed: Mr. Aickin, Mr. Lewis, Mr. Wroughton, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Mr. Fawcett's Night., 1828 Mar 29. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Third Act of Hamlet; The Third Act of Richard II; The Last Act of Romeo and Juliet, and The Invincibles. Individuals listed: Mr. Blanchard, Mr. Kean, Mr. Kemble, Madame Vestris, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Francis the First., 1832 Apr 2. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Color. Additional listings: Barber of Seville and The Hunchback. Individuals listed: Mr. Bennett, Mr. Duruset, Mr. C. Kemble, Mr. J. Mason, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - The Funeral., [1762] Nov 15. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Additional listing: Flora. Individuals listed: Mr. Arthur, Mr. Dyer, Mr. Lowe, Mr. Ridout, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Gymbeline., 1827 Oct 3. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Additional listing: Peter Wilkins. Individuals listed: Mr. Duruset, Mr. Egerton, Mr. Farkley, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Hamlet., 1836 May 20. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Additional listing: Zazezizozu. Individuals listed: Mr. G. Bennett, Mr. Macready, Mr. Pritchard, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Hamlet., 1827 Nov 30. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Additional listings: Alfred the Great and The Seraglio. Individuals listed: Mr. Blanchard, Mr. Duruset, Mr. Egerton, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Hamlet., 1828 Mar 24. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Additional listings: The Invincibles, The Merchant's Wedding, and Othello. Individuals listed: Mr. Blanchard, Miss Stephens, Madame Vestris, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Hamlet, Prince of Denmark., 1821 Oct 8. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Color. Additional listing: Undine. Individuals listed: Mr. Blanchard, Mr. Chapman, Miss E. Dennett, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Harlequin and Number Nip., 1828 Feb 4. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Additional listings: Hamlet and The Merchant's Wedding. Individuals listed: Mr. T. Blanchard, Mr. Egerton, Mr. Ellar, Mr. C. Kemble, Mr. E. J. Parsloe, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Harlequin and the Ogress., 1823 Jan 25. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Additional listing: King Henry the Eighth. Individuals listed: Mr. Bartley, Mr. Claremont, Mr. Macready, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - The Invincibles., 1828 Mar 6. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Additional listing: The Merchant of Venice. Individuals listed: Mr. Kean, Miss Stephen, Madame Vestris, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - The Iron Chest., 1828 Jan 10. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Additional listing: Harlequin and Number Nip, of the Giant Mountain. Individuals listed: Miss Chester, Mr. Kean, Mr. C. Kemble, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Iron Chest., 1828 Feb 21. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Additional listings: The Merchant's Wedding and The Somnambulist. Individuals listed: Mr. Kean, Miss Stephens, Madame Vestris, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Julius Caesar., 1826 May 15. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Additional listings: Diego's Ship at Anchor, Robinson Crusoe, and Three Deep. Individuals listed: Mr. Evans, Mr. Fawcett, Mr. C. Kemble, Mr. Mason, Mr. Warde, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - King John., 1829 Apr 27. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Additional listing: The Devil's Elixir. Individuals listed: Mr. Keeley, Mr. Warde, Mr. Wood, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - King Lear., [no year] Oct 15. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Individuals listed: Mr. Barry, Mr. Ridout, Mr. Ryan, Mr. Sparks, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - King Richard the Third., 1828 Feb 25. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Additional listings: The Invincibles and The Somnambulist. Individuals listed: Mr. Kean, Mr. C. Kemble, Miss Stephens, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent Garden - The Merchant of Venice., 1800 Nov 26. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Color. Additional listing: Il Bondocani. Individuals listed: Mr. Cooke, Mr. Knight, Mr. Pope, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - The Merchant of Venice., 1827 Dec 17. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Additional listings: Freischutz and The Seraglio. Individuals listed: Mr. Blanchard, Mr. Duruset, Mr. Egerton, Mr. Kean, Mr. C. Kemble, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Othello., 1828 Mar 27. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Additional listings: The Invincibles and The Merchant's Wedding. Individuals listed: Mr. Kean, Mr. C. Kemble, Madame Vestris, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Othello., 1828 Apr 25. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Additional listings: The Miller and his Men and The Little Offsprings. Individuals listed: Mr. Kean, Mr. C. Kemble, Madame Vestris, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - The Point of Honour., 1828 May 12. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Additional listings: The Invincibles, Peter Wilkins, and Aladdin. Individuals listed: Mr. Blanchard, Mr. Kemble, Miss Stephens, Madame Vestris, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre-Royal, Covent-Garden - Road to Ruin., 1792 Mar 29. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Additional listing: Rosina. Individuals listed: Mr. Holman, Mr. Lewis, Mr. Quick, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Robinson Crusoe., 1817 Apr 8. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Additional listings: The Conquest of Taranto and King Richard the Third. Individuals listed: Mr. Barrymore, Mr. Booth, Mr. Egerton, Miss O'Neill, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent Garden - The Sexton of Cologne., 1836 Jun 14. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Color. Additional listings: The Persian Prince and Moorish Boy; Robert Macaire. Individuals listed: Mr. Ducrow, Helen Faucit, Mr. Vale, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent Garden - The Spirits of the Moon., 1824 May 10. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Additional listings: King Henry the Fourth and Charles the Second. Individuals listed: Mr. Fawcett, Mr. C. Kemble, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - The Tartar Witch and the Pedlar Boy., 1832 Apr 25. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Color. Additional listings: The Hunchback, Julius Caesar, and The Pass of Kou-Pe-Koo. Individuals listed: Mr. Duruset, Mr. Egerton, Mr. C. Kemble, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Dunlop Street - Aladdin., 1865 Dec 30. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Theatre Royal, Dunlop Street - Jack's Delight., 1866 Jan 15. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Additional listing: Aladdin, The Lamp, and The Light of Other Days. Individuals listed: Ida Idalie, Mr. Kendal, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - Harlequin and Little Thumb., 1832 Jan 23. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Color. Additional listing: Macbeth. Individuals Listed: Mr. Braham, Mr. H. Phillips, Mrs. Wood, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - Distrest Mother., 1819 Mar 27. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Additional listings: Castle of Wonders, Rival Soldiers, and other events. Individuals listed: Mr. Cooke, Mr. D. Fischer, Edmund Kean, Mr. H. Kemble, Mr. R. Phillips, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - The Cattle-Spectre., 1800 Feb 1. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Additional listing: Of Age To-morrow. Individuals listed: Mr. Bannister, Mr. Barrymore, Mr. Cory, Mr. Kemble, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - The Coronation., 1821 Aug 7. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Color. Additional listings: The Mountaineers and Fortune's Frolic. Individuals listed: Mr. T. Cooke, Mr. Cubitt, Mr. Knight, Mr. Russell, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Dury Lane - The Earl of Essex., [no year] Jan 17. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Individuals listed: Mr. Davies, Mr. Holland, Mr. Sheridan, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - Formosa., 1869 Sep 13. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Additional listing: The Belles of the Kitchen. Individuals listed: Mr. Barrett, Mrs. Billington, David Fischer, Henry Irving, Kathrerine Rodgers, John Rouse, Britain Wright, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - Hamlet., 18[?]5 Mar 17. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - King Richard III., 1827 Jun 18. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - The Merchant of Venice., 1827 Jun 14. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Additional listing: The Magpie. Individuals listed: Mr. Cooper, Mr. Kean, Mr. Mercer, Mr. Pope, Mr. Powell, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - The Minister and the Mercer., 1834 Apr 29. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Additional listings: Secret Service and Saradanapalus. Individuals listed: Mr. Cooper, Mr. W. Farren, Mr. Mathews, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - More Ways than One., 1792 Jul 6. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Additional listing: Richard Coeur de Lion. Individuals listed: Mr. Franklin, Mr. King, Mr. Sidney, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - Othello., 1814 Jun 25. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Color. Additional listing: Flitch of Bacon. Individuals listed: Mr. Decamp, Mr. Dowton, Mr. Elrington, Mr. Kean, Mr. Mountain, Mr. R. Phillips, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - Othello., 1830 Jan 1. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Additional listing: Jack in the Box. Individuals listed: Mr. Kean, Mr. Lee, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury-Lane - The Prisoner., 1796 Dec 3. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Additional listings: The Panel and The Adopted Child. Individuals listed: Mr. Bannister, Mr. Dignum, Mr. Kelly, Mr. Sedgwick, Mr. Suett, Mr. Trueman, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - The Secret., 1799 Nov 19. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Additional listing: My Grandmother. Individuals listed: Mr. Bannister, Mr. Barrymore, Mr. Downton, Mr. C. Kemble, Mr. Sedgwick, Mr. Suett, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - The Secret., 1800 8 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Additional listing: The Romance of Lodoiska. Individuals listed: Mr. Barrymore, Mr. Downton, Mr. C. Kemble, Mr. Palmer, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - The Slave., 1827 Oct 19. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Color. Additional listings: The Gambler's Fate; Guy Mannering; The Lord of the Manor; The Merry Wives of Windsor; and Pizarro. Individuals listed: Mr. Braham, Mr. Kean, Miss Grant, Miss Paton, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - Timon of Athens., 1816 Nov 11. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Additional listings: The Bridal of Flora and The Watch-word. Individuals listed: Mr. Bengough, Mr. P. Cooke, Mr. Kean, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane - The Will., 1800 Feb 8. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Additional listings: Scotch Ghost and The Apprentice. Individuals listed: Mr. Bannister, Mr. Hollingsworth, Mr. King, Mr. Mellon, Mr. Suett, Mr. Wewitzer, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Edinburgh - Tragedy of Bertram., 1820 Jul 27. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Additional listing: The Weathercock. Individuals listed: Mr. Calcraft, Mr. Kean, Miss M. Nicol, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Hay-Market - Taming the Shrew photograph of illustration., undated. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Theatre Royal, Hay-Market - King Lear., 1832 Aug 6. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Additional listings: The Hunchback, The Padlock, and Second Thoughts. Individuals listed: Mr. Bartlett, Mr. Coveney, Mr. Kean, Mr. Strickland, and others.
  - Theatre-Royal, Hay-Market - Romeo and Juliet., 1855 Apr 27. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Additional listing: The New Haymarket Spring Meeting. Individuals listed: Miss Cushman, Miss Swanborough, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Manchester - The Belle's Stratagem., 1803 Jan 14. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Additional listing: Paul and Virginia. Individuals listed: Mr. Huddart, Mr. Mills, Mr. Simms, Mr. Ward, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, New Adelphi - The Colleen Bawn., [1862] Dec 10. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Individuals listed: Dion Boucicault, Agnes Robertson, Mr. J. G. Warde, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, New Adelphi - Rip Van Winkle., undated. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Additional listings: Betty Martin, Good For Nothing, and Widow's Victim. Individuals listed: Joseph Jefferson, Alfred Mellon, Felix Rogers, Jenny Wilmore, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Sadler's Wells - Death Omen., 1840 Feb 24. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Additional listings: The Chiarini Family and Boatswain's Whistle. Individuals listed: Mr. Dry, Mr. R. Honner, Mr. Stilt, Mr. Williams, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Sadler's Wells - Timon Of Athens., 1851 Oct 20. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Additional listing: Katherine and Petruchio. Individuals listed: Mr. Hoskins, Mr. Phelps, Mr. F. Robinson, and others.
  - Theatre, Sheffield - Blanche of Jersey., 1838 Nov 29. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Additional listings: Forest of Bondy, and other events. Individuals listed: Mr. Blanchard, Mr. Cony, and others.
  - Victoria Theatre - Harlequin and Hot Codlings., 1844 Dec 26. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Color. Additional listings: Poverty and The Road-Side Inn. Individuals listed: John Herbert, Mr. T.H. Higgie, Henry Howard, Mr. J.T. Johnson, Mr. W. Searile, Mr. Osbaldiston, and others.
  - Victoria Theatre - Richard Plantagenet., 1845 Oct 13. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Color. Additional listing: Jack Sheppard. Individuals listed: Mr. E. Edwards, Mr. Gaston, Mr. J.T. Johnson, Mr. E. F. Saville, and others.
- Scrapbooks, Illustrations, and Photographs., circa 1830s-circa 1840s, 1887-1888, 1904-1905, 1951, and undated.
  The series consists of five scrapbooks and loose illustrations and photographs. The scrapbooks represent 19th and early 20th century theatre. Two scrapbooks contain illustrations/caricatures and photographs; one scrapbook is primarily autographs; one scrapbook is cut outs from American theater playbills; and one scrapbook consists of cut out characters for toy theatre representing Robinson Cursoe, Black-eyed Susan, and Hamlet. The loose illustrations and photographs represent performers, theatres, and costumes. Additionally, included is one letter from Macready to Count D’Orsay.
  - von Allers Circus illustrations (6 items)., 1887. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Edwin Booth photographs (cabinet cards) (2 items)., undated. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Color Costume Plates (3 items)., undated. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Full Dress of a Gentleman; Half Dress; and Promenade Dress.
  - Color Figures for Toy Theatres illustrations (3 items)., undated. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Pollock's New Panto Mime Characters; Redington's New Sixteens; and Skelt's New Demons.
  - Mr. T. P. Cooke as Ben Backstay illustration., undated. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Mr. Creswich as Hamlet tuppence color illustration., undated. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Jumbo the Great Elephant and his keeper Scott chromolithographic poster., undated. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Drawn from life by A.H. Wray.
  - Mr. Kean illustration., undated. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Mr. Kean as Bajazet illustration., undated. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Charles Kean illustrations (7 items)., undated. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Photographs of illustrations representing A Midsummer's Night Dream and King John (1852 Feb). Illustration of Mr. Kean as Brutus and Richard the Third.
  - Edmund Kean illustrations (original and printed) (6 items)., undated. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mr. Kemble illustration., undated. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Macready letter to Count D'Orsay., undated. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Handwriting difficult to decipher.
  - Mr. Phelps and Miss Glyn illustration., undated. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Prints of theatres and actors (6 items)., undated. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Mr. C. Kemble as Falconbridge; Old Price Riots in Drury Lane; Mr. Phelps as Sir John Falstaff; The Rt. Hon.; The Earl of Barrymore and Capt. Wathen as Scrub and Archer; and The Singles.
  - Scrapbook., undated. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Inside cover annotated Emma F. [indecipherable last name] May 1877. Written over Wilfred Brandon's Collection. Cut out illustrations of Robinson Cursoe, Black-eyed Susan, and Hamlet. With printed sheet music titled Davidson's Little Songs for Little Singers Buttercups and Daisies and Davidson's Little Songs for Little Singers Farmer Went Trotting.
  - Scrapbook., circa mid-1830s-1840s. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    With pieces of playbills, letters, cut outs from daily advertisements, and autographs.
  - Scrapbook., [circa late 1800s]. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Inside cover annotated Arthur Williams. Cut outs of photographs and caricatures of actors and/or actors in scenes. Some actors identified: George Barrett, Mr. J.B. Buckstone, Charles Mathews, and others.
  - Scrapbook., [1887-1888]. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    American playbills. Front cover embossed with color illustration of dogs.
  - Scrapbook., 1904-1905. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Theater and concert programs and photographs of actors and/or actors in scenes.
  - St. Stephen's Review Presentation Cartoon., 1887 Jan 29. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Coloured lithographic cartoon by Tom Merry. Caption reads: JUST A' GOIN' TO BEGIN! W. H. Smith (loq.) Walk up, gentlemen, walk up-no waiting, no loss of time! All in to begin!
  - Tamburlaine the Great photographs on postcards (6 items)., 1951. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Some actors identified: Jill Balcon, David Greene, Leo McKern, Lee Montague, Marget Rawlings, Reginald Tate, David Waller, and Donald Wolfit.